Subject Files
Marist Archives and Special Collections
- Subject Files, 2.1.3.6
  - Subject files: High Adventure with Lowell Thomas (New Guinea) [includes one color photograph], 1957 November; 5 (Box 1547)
    - Note: [press release] ON DECK FOR ADVENTURE; Lowell Thomas relaxes on river boat taking him and camera crew up the wild Sepik River to photograph Stone Age savages in hitherto unexplored area of New Guinea for first installment of the new television adventure series, "High Adventure with Lowell Thomas," which will be shown over the CBS television network on Tuesday, November 12, 8:00 to 9:00 P.M. EST, under the sponsorship of the United Motors System and Delco-Remy divisions of General Motors, 14
    - WHAT'S THE PITCH?; Two baffled head-hunters deep in unexplored New Guinea territory watch world-famous explorer and author Lowell Thomas record commentary for the first episode of the new television series, "High Adventure with Lowell Thomas," Which will be presented over the CBS television network Tuesday, November 12, 8:00 to 9:00 P.M. EST. The one-hour film in full color depicts initial impact of civilization on Stone Age savages who have not changed their living habits for the past 2,000 years, 15
    - Note: [press release] WHAT'S THE PITCH?; Two baffled head-hunters deep in unexplored New Guinea territory watch world-famous explorer and author Lowell Thomas record commentary for the first episode of the new television series, "High Adventure with Lowell Thomas," Which will be presented over the CBS television network Tuesday, November 12, 8:00 to 9:00 P.M. EST. The one-hour film in full color depicts initial impact of civilization on Stone Age savages who have not changed their living habits for the past 2,000 years, 16
    - Two baffled head-hunters..., 17
    - [13 copies] Two baffled head-hunters..., 18
  - Subject files: High Adventure with Lowell Thomas (New Guinea), 1957 November; 6 (Box 1547)
    - Integration in New Guinea; Father William Ross A.V.D. and one of his parishioners at Mt. Hagen, New Guinea, 1
    - Verso: Integration in New Guinea; Father William Ross A.V.D. and one of his parishioners at Mt. Hagen, New Guinea, 1-verso
    - Bird of Paradise, New Guinea, 2
    - Verso: Bird of Paradise, New Guinea, 2-verso
    - [Lowell Thomas with two women in New Guinea], [6 copies], 3
    - [Lowell Thomas and two natives looking at a canoe in New Guinea], 4
    - [Lowell Thomas and his camera crew in New Guinea], 5
    - [Camera crew filming a woman carving out a log], 6
    - [Lowell Thomas sitting with a tribesman in New Guinea], 7
    - [Lowell Thomas sitting with a tribe holding arrows in New Guinea], 8
    - [Lowell Thomas standing with two New Guinea tribesmen], 9
    - [Lowell Thomas standing with two New Guinea tribesmen], 10
    - [Lowell Thomas standing with a group of tribespeople in New Guinea], 11
    - [Two New Guinea tribespeople], 12
    - [New Guinea tribeswoman with a mortar and pestle], 13
    - [On the set of Lowell Thomas's High Adventures in New Guinea], 14
    - [Lowell Thomas and a member of his crew talking in New Guinea], 15
    - [Member of Lowell Thomas's crew in New Guinea], 16
    - [New Guinea tribeswomen dancing], 17
    - [Various photos from Lowell Thomas's "High Adventure" to New Guinea], 18
    - [New Guinea family sitting on steps], 19
    - [New Guinea tribesmen wearing paint], 20
    - [Various photos of New Guinea tribespeople dancing], 21
    - [Photos of New Guinea tribespeople from Lowell Thomas's High Adventure], 22
    - [Photos of New Guinea tribespeople from Lowell Thomas's High Adventure], 23
    - "Lowell Thomas and Stone Age Man", 24
    - Verso: Lowell Thomas and Stone Age Man, 24-verso
  - Subject files: High Adventure with Lowell Thomas (New Guinea), 1957 November; 7 (Box 1547)
    - [Lowell Thomas with a tribe in New Guinea, 1957], 1
    - New Guinea 1957, 2
    - Verso: New Guinea 1957, 2-verso
    - [Lowell Thomas with a tribe in New Guinea, 1957], 3
    - L.T. with cannibals in New Guinea [3 copies], 4
    - Verso: L.T. with cannibals in New Guinea, 4-verso
    - L.T. with cannibals in New Guinea jungle, 5
    - Verso: L.T. with cannibals in New Guinea jungle, 5-verso
    - Caption: I didn't stay for dinner! Lowell, 6
    - [Lowell Thomas with a tribe in New Guinea, 1957], [9 copies], 7
  - Subject files: High Adventure with Lowell Thomas (North Pole), 1957 December; 8 (Box 1547)
    - ARCTIC PIONEERS REUNITE; New York, N. Y., August 31, 1957 - Four pioneers of Arctic exploration - Admiral Donald B. MacMillan, Sir Hubert Wilkins, Peter Freuchen and Col. Bernt Balchen - left Idlewild Airport with Lowell Thomas over the weekend on first step of a photography expedition to polar regions for new television adventure series, "High Adventure with Lowell Thomas," which will make bow over CBS-TV network early in November. This is first meeting of quartet who will retrace trails in icy northern wastes which they pioneered and study new techniques of living in Arctic, which is now important American line of defense. (Left to right are shown: Adm. Donald B. MacMillan, Sir Hubert Wilkins, Peter Freuchen, Lowell Thomas, Col. Bernt Balchen and Gilbert Ralston.), 1
    - Note: [press release] ARCTIC PIONEERS REUNITE; New York, N. Y., August 31, 1957 - Four pioneers of Arctic exploration - Admiral Donald B. MacMillan, Sir Hubert Wilkins, Peter Freuchen and Col. Bernt Balchen - left Idlewild Airport with Lowell Thomas over the weekend on first step of a photography expedition to polar regions for new television adventure series, "High Adventure with Lowell Thomas," which will make bow over CBS-TV network early in November. This is first meeting of quartet who will retrace trails in icy northern wastes which they pioneered and study new techniques of living in Arctic, which is now important American line of defense. (Left to right are shown: Adm. Donald B. MacMillan, Sir Hubert Wilkins, Peter Freuchen, Lowell Thomas, Col. Bernt Balchen and Gilbert Ralston.), 2
    - ARCTIC PIONEERS REUNITE, 3
    - Caption: signed by: Hubert Wilkins, Lowell Thomas, Bernt Balchen, Donald MacMillan, 4
    - [Lowell Thomas (on left) and Bernt Balchen (second from right) with two other men headed for the North Pole ], [2 copies], 5
    - [Lowell Thomas and his crew looking at a map while heading to the North Pole], 6
    - [Lowell Thomas and his crew looking at a map while heading to the North Pole], [2 copies], 7
    - [Lowell Thomas and his crew looking at a map while heading to the North Pole], 8
    - [Lowell Thomas and the other members of his crew looking at a map while they head to the North Pole], 9
    - [Lowell Thomas and a member of his crew in the North Pole], 10
    - [Lowell Thomas and a member of his crew in the North Pole], [2 copies], 11
    - ARCTIC PIONEERS ON "HIGH ADVENTURE" DEC. 23; Arctic Pioneers Admiral Donald MacMillan, sole survivor of the first expedition to the North Pole in 1909; Col. Bernt Balchen, Arctic flyer; Lowell Thomas; and Sir Hubert Wilkins, who first tried to reach the Pole by submarine (shown here, left to right), will be seen on "High Adventure with Lowell Thomas" (CBS Television, 10:00-11:00 PM, EST) Monday, December 23.; As they help Thomas and his production crew navigate the icy trails of the Arctic, the pioneers of the polar regions relive High Adventure" themselves. Lowell Thomas, Jr. will produce the program, 12
    - Note: [press release] ARCTIC PIONEERS ON "HIGH ADVENTURE" DEC. 23; Arctic Pioneers Admiral Donald MacMillan, sole survivor of the first expedition to the North Pole in 1909; Col. Bernt Balchen, Arctic flyer; Lowell Thomas; and Sir Hubert Wilkins, who first tried to reach the Pole by submarine (shown here, left to right), will be seen on "High Adventure with Lowell Thomas" (CBS Television, 10:00-11:00 PM, EST) Monday, December 23.; As they help Thomas and his production crew navigate the icy trails of the Arctic, the pioneers of the polar regions relive High Adventure" themselves. Lowell Thomas, Jr. will produce the program, 13
    - ARCTIC PIONEERS ON "HIGH ADVENTURE" DEC. 23 [4 copies], 14
    - TWO FOR THE SHOW: Admiral Donald B. MacMillan (left) and Lowell Thomas discuss old-time Arctic adventure as they fly over the North Pole in the second episode of "High Adventure with Lowell Thomas," which will be colorcast over the CBS-TV network Monday, December 23rd, 10:00-11:00 p.m., EST. Admiral MacMillan, who was a member of the Peary polar expedition in 1909 and was awarded a special Congressional medal for his efforts at that time, accompanied Thomas on his camera expedition to the frozen wastes. Other pioneer explorers Sir Hurbet Wilkins and Col. Bernt Balchen will be seen in "High Adventure with Lowell Thomas," which is sponsored by the United Motors System and Delco-Remy division of General Motors, 15
    - Note: [press release] TWO FOR THE SHOW: Admiral Donald B. MacMillan (left) and Lowell Thomas discuss old-time Arctic adventure as they fly over the North Pole in the second episode of "High Adventure with Lowell Thomas," which will be colorcast over the CBS-TV network Monday, December 23rd, 10:00-11:00 p.m., EST. Admiral MacMillan, who was a member of the Peary polar expedition in 1909 and was awarded a special Congressional medal for his efforts at that time, accompanied Thomas on his camera expedition to the frozen wastes. Other pioneer explorers Sir Hurbet Wilkins and Col. Bernt Balchen will be seen in "High Adventure with Lowell Thomas," which is sponsored by the United Motors System and Delco-Remy division of General Motors, 16
    - [2 copies] LIKE FATHER, LIKE SON: Ever since he was a youngster, Lowell Thomas, Jr. has traveled to the far and mysterious spots of the earth with his illustrious Father. Here they check on a map of the "Top of the World" before taking off on a photography expedition to the north Pole for scenes in the second episode of "High Adventure with Lowell Thomas, " which comes to the nation's living rooms in color over the CBS network on Monday, December 23rd, 10:00-11:00 p.m., EST, under the sponsorship of the United Motors System and Delco-Remy division of General Motors, 17
    - Note: [press release] LIKE FATHER, LIKE SON: Ever since he was a youngster, Lowell Thomas, Jr. has traveled to the far and mysterious spots of the earth with his illustrious Father. Here they check on a map of the "Top of the World" before taking off on a photography expedition to the north Pole for scenes in the second episode of "High Adventure with Lowell Thomas, " which comes to the nation's living rooms in color over the CBS network on Monday, December 23rd, 10:00-11:00 p.m., EST, under the sponsorship of the United Motors System and Delco-Remy division of General Motors, 18
    - [4 copies] L.T. at the North Pole (with Bernt Balchen, Admiral Donald MacMillan, L.T. Jr., and Sir Hubert Wilkins), 19
    - Verso: L.T. at the North Pole (with Bernt Balchen, Admiral Donald MacMillan, L.T. Jr., and Sir Hubert Wilkins), 19-verso
    - FIND "HIGH ADVENTURE" IN ARCTIC AREAS: Col. Bernt Balchen, the first man to fly over the North and South poles, poses with Lowell Thomas at Elmendorf Air Base, Alaska, before filming of the second installment of "High Adventure with Lowell Thomas" (CBS Television, 10:00-11:00 PM, EST) Monday, December 23. Col. Balchen, who helps guide the Thomas expedition into the North Lands, is one of America's top aviation experts-- and like many others, is well aware of the strategic importance of Arctic bases for the air defense of the North American continent. In the above picture, the pair display their professional badge-- the flag of the Explorers' Club, the world-wide symbol of "High Adventure", 20
    - Note: [press release] FIND "HIGH ADVENTURE" IN ARCTIC AREAS: Col. Bernt Balchen, the first man to fly over the North and South poles, poses with Lowell Thomas at Elmendorf Air Base, Alaska, before filming of the second installment of "High Adventure with Lowell Thomas" (CBS Television, 10:00-11:00 PM, EST) Monday, December 23. Col. Balchen, who helps guide the Thomas expedition into the North Lands, is one of America's top aviation experts-- and like many others, is well aware of the strategic importance of Arctic bases for the air defense of the North American continent. In the above picture, the pair display their professional badge-- the flag of the Explorers' Club, the world-wide symbol of "High Adventure", 21
    - [press release] LOWELL THOMAS HITS ARCTIC TRAIL: The second installment of "High Adventure with Lowell Thomas" (CBS Television, 10:00- 11:00 PM, EST) Monday, December 23, will follow Thomas and his television band as they trek to "The Top of the World "-the North Pole. The program will visit America's northernmost air defenses-from Alaska's Cape Lisburne along the DEW line to the Greenland Ice Cap, where Mr. Thomas is seen in the above picture, 22
    - Note: LOWELL THOMAS HITS ARCTIC TRAIL: The second installment of "High Adventure with Lowell Thomas" (CBS Television, 10:00- 11:00 PM, EST) Monday, December 23, will follow Thomas and his television band as they trek to "The Top of the World "-the North Pole. The program will visit America's northernmost air defenses-from Alaska's Cape Lisburne along the DEW line to the Greenland Ice Cap, where Mr. Thomas is seen in the above picture, 23
    - LOWELL ON HIGH: Sitting practically on top of the world, Lowell Thomas poses for camera study during filming of second installment of his television adventure series, "High Adventure with Lowell Thomas," above the Arctic Circle. Behind him is dome housing radar apparatus on so-called "Dew-Line" to warn our armed forces of the approach of unidentified aircraft. "High Adventure with Lowell Thomas" is sponsored by the United Motors System and Delco-Remy division of General Motors and will be telecast in full color for one hour over the CBS-TV network, Monday, December 23rd, 10:00-11:00 p.m., EST, 24
    - Note: [press release] LOWELL ON HIGH: Sitting practically on top of the world, Lowell Thomas poses for camera study during filming of second installment of his television adventure series, "High Adventure with Lowell Thomas," above the Arctic Circle. Behind him is dome housing radar apparatus on so-called "Dew-Line" to warn our armed forces of the approach of unidentified aircraft. "High Adventure with Lowell Thomas" is sponsored by the United Motors System and Delco-Remy division of General Motors and will be telecast in full color for one hour over the CBS-TV network, Monday, December 23rd, 10:00-11:00 p.m., EST, 25
    - "HIGH ADVENTURE" GOES FOR A SWIM-AT 60 DEGREES BELOW: "Come on in, the water's fine," one Navy Frogman might be saying to the other, in the second episode of "High Adventure with Lowell Thomas" (CBS Television, 10:00-11:00 PM, EST) Monday, December 23. When Lowell Thomas and his band of sourdoughs trek to the icy wasters of the Arctic they capture on film the heroic exploits of the dare-devil divers-the men of the Navy demolition squads who blast ice flows free with 18,000 pounds of TNT and keep America's vital supply lines along the Polar Sea open for shipping, 26
    - Note: [press release] "HIGH ADVENTURE" GOES FOR A SWIM-AT 60 DEGREES BELOW: "Come on in, the water's fine," one Navy Frogman might be saying to the other, in the second episode of "High Adventure with Lowell Thomas" (CBS Television, 10:00-11:00 PM, EST) Monday, December 23. When Lowell Thomas and his band of sourdoughs trek to the icy wasters of the Arctic they capture on film the heroic exploits of the dare-devil divers-the men of the Navy demolition squads who blast ice flows free with 18,000 pounds of TNT and keep America's vital supply lines along the Polar Sea open for shipping, 27
    - LOWELL THOMAS, JR. VISITS ESKIMOS IN SECOND EPISODE OF "HIGH ADVENTURE," DEC. 23: Lowell Thomas, Jr. makes his television production debut as the producer of the Arctic chapter of "High Adventure with Lowell Thomas" (CBS Television, 10:00-11:00 PM, EST) Monday, December 23. Above, he visits an Eskimo family near Kotzebue, Alaska. All "armchair adventures" will see ancient tribal customs as these remote natives ten their nomadic reindeer herds in the far North. Other parts of the exciting program will show an Air Force scramble of F-89 Scorpion jets, as they battle mythical enemy planes; the radar warning posts of the distant DEW line and the Greenland Ice cap, 28
    - Note: [press release] LOWELL THOMAS, JR. VISITS ESKIMOS IN SECOND EPISODE OF "HIGH ADVENTURE," DEC. 23: Lowell Thomas, Jr. makes his television production debut as the producer of the Arctic chapter of "High Adventure with Lowell Thomas" (CBS Television, 10:00-11:00 PM, EST) Monday, December 23. Above, he visits an Eskimo family near Kotzebue, Alaska. All "armchair adventures" will see ancient tribal customs as these remote natives ten their nomadic reindeer herds in the far North. Other parts of the exciting program will show an Air Force scramble of F-89 Scorpion jets, as they battle mythical enemy planes; the radar warning posts of the distant DEW line and the Greenland Ice cap, 29
    - [Lowell Thomas with those who accompanied him on his adventure to the North Pole], 30
    - [Lowell Thomas standing in front of a stuffed bear on display], 31
    - [Lowell Thomas and others standing in front of a map of Alaska], 32
    - [Lowell Thomas and a man standing in front of an old automobile], 33
  - Subject files: High Adventure with Lowell Thomas (Timbuktu to Mozambique and on to Madagascar) [includes color photograph], 1958 January; 9 (Box 1547)
    - READY TO GO-Lowell Thomas gets ready to direct camera operations at a huge taxidermy establishment in Kenya, Africa for a special sequence in the third episode of "High Adventure with Lowell Thomas," which will be seen on the CBS television network Wednesday, January 22nd, 8:00-9:00 p.m., EST. The hour-long color film will give TV-viewers a new insight into many corners of Africa which have never been photographed before. "High Adventure with Lowell Thomas" is sponsored by the United Motors System and Delco-Remy division of General Motors, 1
    - Note: [press release] READY TO GO-Lowell Thomas gets ready to direct camera operations at a huge taxidermy establishment in Kenya, Africa for a special sequence in the third episode of "High Adventure with Lowell Thomas," which will be seen on the CBS television network Wednesday, January 22nd, 8:00-9:00 p.m., EST. The hour-long color film will give TV-viewers a new insight into many corners of Africa which have never been photographed before. "High Adventure with Lowell Thomas" is sponsored by the United Motors System and Delco-Remy division of General Motors, 2
    - CAMELS ARE COMING-Lowell Thomas gets into the act himself as he rides a camel during the filming of tough camel troops of the French army in the Sahara Desert outside of Timbuktu for "High Adventure with Lowell Thomas," which will be colorcast Wednesday, January 22nd, 8:00-9:00 p.m., EST over the CBS television network. The third "High Adventure with Lowell Thomas" in the monthly series sponsored by the United Motors System and Delco-Remy division of General Motors is devoted to the "heartline" of Africa from Timbuktu to Madagascar, via Kenya and Uganda, 3
    - Note: [press release] CAMELS ARE COMING-Lowell Thomas gets into the act himself as he rides a camel during the filming of tough camel troops of the French army in the Sahara Desert outside of Timbuktu for "High Adventure with Lowell Thomas," which will be colorcast Wednesday, January 22nd, 8:00-9:00 p.m., EST over the CBS television network. The third "High Adventure with Lowell Thomas" in the monthly series sponsored by the United Motors System and Delco-Remy division of General Motors is devoted to the "heartline" of Africa from Timbuktu to Madagascar, via Kenya and Uganda, 4
    - TAKES A BREATHER: Lowell Thomas takes time-out during the color filming of French native desert troops outside the ancient slave town of Timbuktu on the edge of the Sahara Desert for scenes in the third episode of "High Adventure with Lowell Thomas," which will be shown on the CBS television network Wednesday, January 22nd, 8:00-9:00 p.m., EST. These troops, mounted on camels, have the reputation of being the toughest in the world. "High Adventure with Lowell Thomas" is sponsored by the United Motors System and Delco-Remy division of General Motors, 5
    - Note: [press release] TAKES A BREATHER: Lowell Thomas takes time-out during the color filming of French native desert troops outside the ancient slave town of Timbuktu on the edge of the Sahara Desert for scenes in the third episode of "High Adventure with Lowell Thomas," which will be shown on the CBS television network Wednesday, January 22nd, 8:00-9:00 p.m., EST. These troops, mounted on camels, have the reputation of being the toughest in the world. "High Adventure with Lowell Thomas" is sponsored by the United Motors System and Delco-Remy division of General Motors, 6
    - CAMELS ARE COMING: Lowell Thomas gets into the act himself as he rides a camel during the filming of tough camel troops of the French army in the Sahara Desert outside Timbuktu for "High Adventure with Lowell Thomas," which will be colorcast Wednesday, January 22nd, 8:00-9:00 p.m., EST over the CBS television network. The third "High Adventure with Lowell Thomas" in the monthly series sponsored by the United Motors System and Delco-Remy division of General Motors is devoted to the "heartline" of Africa form Timbuktu to Madagascar, via Kenya and Uganda, 7
    - Note: [press release] CAMELS ARE COMING: Lowell Thomas gets into the act himself as he rides a camel during the filming of tough camel troops of the French army in the Sahara Desert outside Timbuktu for "High Adventure with Lowell Thomas," which will be colorcast Wednesday, January 22nd, 8:00-9:00 p.m., EST over the CBS television network. The third "High Adventure with Lowell Thomas" in the monthly series sponsored by the United Motors System and Delco-Remy division of General Motors is devoted to the "heartline" of Africa form Timbuktu to Madagascar, via Kenya and Uganda, 8
    - Note: [with 9.7] L.T. aboard a camel with the Tuaregs - in the southern Sahara - near Timbuctu, 9
    - This was in Timbuctu with the French camel corps, 10
    - This was in Timbuctu with the French camel corps, 11
    - Note: This was in Timbuctu with the French camel corps, 12
  - Subject files: High Adventure with Lowell Thomas (Tibet), 1958 February; 10 (Box 1547)
    - TALL GIFT: Lowell Thomas accepts ceremonial gift from Rimshi Dote, one of the Tibetan district governors, who is almost seven feet tall, enroute to Lhasa, the forbidden capital of Tibet. Thomas and his son, Lowell Thomas, Jr., were the 7th and 8th Americans allowed to visit that strange country which forms the basis of Episode No. 4 in the CBS television series, "High Adventure with Lowell Thomas," (CBS-TV, Tuesday, February 25, 8:00-9:00 p.m., EST), 1
    - Note: [press release] TALL GIFT: Lowell Thomas accepts ceremonial gift from Rimshi Dote, one of the Tibetan district governors, who is almost seven feet tall, enroute to Lhasa, the forbidden capital of Tibet. Thomas and his son, Lowell Thomas, Jr., were the 7th and 8th Americans allowed to visit that strange country which forms the basis of Episode No. 4 in the CBS television series, "High Adventure with Lowell Thomas," (CBS-TV, Tuesday, February 25, 8:00-9:00 p.m., EST), 2